Guide to the Myra H. Strober Papers SC1344
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Myra H. Strober Papers
1970-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Strober, Myra H.
SC1344
9.5 Linear Feet
Collection consists of Strober's professional files, teaching materials, writing files, and audiovisual materials. Also included are 10,890 megabytes of Strober’s digital files.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Myra Strober, 2017.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of Strober's professional files, teaching materials, writing files, and audiovisual materials. Also included are 10,890 megabytes of Strober’s digital files.
Biographical / Historical
Myra Strober is Professor Emerita at the School of Education at Stanford University and Professor of Economics at the Graduate School of Business at Stanford University (by courtesy). Strober is a labor economist whose research focus is on gender issues at the workplace, work and family, and multidisciplinarity in higher education. She is the author of numerous articles on occupational segregation, women in the professions and management, the economics of childcare, feminist economics and the teaching of economics. In 2016 Strober published the book "Sharing the Work: What My Family and Career Taught Me About Breaking Through (and Holding the Door Open for Others)." Biographical information excerpted from: https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/faculty-research/faculty/myra-h-strober
Women economists -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Strober, Myra H.; Strober, Myra H.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Business. Faculty
- Papers, 1970-2016; Accession ARCH-2017-225
  - Professional Files
    - Vitae, 2017-03 (Box 1)
    - Undergraduate Papers and Syllabi (Cornell University) (Box 1)
    - Papers from Graduate School (MIT) (Box 1)
    - Women in Academia (Stanford, Berkeley, Harvard), 1970-1975 (Box 1)
    - Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP) (Box 1)
    - CSWEP Newsletters (Box 1)
    - Women in Management Conference - Graduate School of Business, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Center for Research on Women at Stanford (CROW) (Box 1)
    - Development of Feminist Studies at Stanford University (Box 1)
    - Institute for Research on Women and Gender (IRWG) (Box 1)
    - Myra’s Tenure and Promotion Decisions, 1978, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Institute for Finance and Governance (IFG) at Stanford School of Education, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Newsclippings (Box 2)
    - School of Education (Box 2)
    - International Association for Feminist Economics (IAFFE) (Box 2)
    - Report on Stanford Provost’s Committee on the Recruitment and Retention of Women, 1993 (Box 2)
    - The Wendt Case (Connecticut Divorce Case) Expert Witness testimony and Judge’s Decision, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Spencer Foundation Conference on Women’s Studies, 1999 (Box 2)
    - MIT Meeting on Women Faculty at Research Universities (Box 3)
    - Other Research University Reports on Women Faculty (Box 3)
    - Talks (Box 4)
    - Russell Sage Grant on Occupational Segregation, 1980-1985 (Box 3)
    - Retirement, 2007 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Writing
    - Chapters for Unfinished Book (Box 5)
    - Papers (many of these are published in difficult to find places) (Box 5)
    - Fear of Feedback (Box 5)
    - Feminist Economics (Box 6)
    - Atlantic Philanthropies (Box 6)
  - Teaching
    - Stanford Graduate School of Business (Box 3)
    - Course Readers for Work and Family, 2011, 2016 (Box 4)
    - Stanford Joint Degree Program – MA in Education and MBA (Box 3)
    - Work and Family Class at Graduate School of Business (Box 3)
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Women in Management – An Ongoing Revolution: A History of Women at the Stanford Business School, 2006; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 6)
    - Honoring Myra Strober - Introduction and Welcome and Panel on Women’s Education, Work and Families, 2007-05-05; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 6)
    - Honoring Myra Strober - Panel on Institutional Change at Retirement Symposium, and Conversation with Lisa Petrides, and Strober Closing Remarks, 2007 May 5; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 6)
    - Myra’s Class, 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
    - Myra Teaching, 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
    - Executive Briefings – Stanford GSB – Fear of Feedback, Myra Strober and Jay Jackman (52 minutes), 2004; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
    - Myra on Phil Donahue Show, 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
    - Graduate School of Business – Women’s History Month Video Project, 1992 Mar; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Computer Files
    - Myra Strober Retirement Symposium, 78 computer files (JPG)
    - Strober Visiting Lectureship at Tamkang University, Taipei, 2000-05; 51 computer files (TIF)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-237
  - IAFFE History, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lyman songs, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Signs song, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Songs for Alice Supton, 1993 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CROW, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charlie Meyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Downing, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes of thanks, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IAFFE conference talk, 2012 Jun (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Defining feminism, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Feminist pubs, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Chilly Classroom Climate: A Guide to Improve the Education of Women, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Final Report of the Provost's Committee on the Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)